usbr.gov 2006-06-13

# Bureau of Reclamation: Privacy Policy

**Bureau of Reclamation  
U.S. Department of the Interior  
Privacy Policy for this Website**

* * *

This is how we will handle information we learn about you from your visit to our website. The information we receive depends upon what you do when visiting our site. 

If you visit our site to read or download information, such as consumer brochures or press releases: 

    We collect and store _only_ the following information about you: the name of the domain from which you access the Internet (for example, aol.com, if you are connecting from an America Online account, or princeton.edu if you are connecting from Princeton University's domain); the date and time you access our site; and the Internet address of the website from which you linked directly to our site. **We do not store any personal identifiers. This information is not stored in any particular fashion, but is part of a systems log file.**
    For site management, information is collected for statistical purposes. This government computer system uses software programs to create summary statistics, which are used for such purposes as assessing what information is of most and least interest, determining technical design specifications, and identifying system performance or problem areas. We use the information we collect to measure the number of visitors to the different sections of our site, and to help us make our site more useful to visitors. **This information is only used internally, does not contain personal identifiers, and will only be used for internal management purposes.**

If you identify yourself by sending an E-mail or filling out a questionnaire or guestbook:

    You also may decide to send us personally identifying information, for example, in an electronic mail message containing a comment. We use personally identifying information from consumers in various ways to further our **customers' protection and to provide better service. This may be to correct broken links that you have identified or provide additional information that you have requested.**   
**  
Any information that we collect via a questionnaire or a guestbook may be subject to disclosure, but will be handled in accordance with the requirements of the[Privacy Act](http://www.usdoj.gov/04foia/04_7_1.html) and the [Freedom of Information Act](http://www.usbr.gov/foia/) to ensure the greatest protection of personal privacy in the face of any required disclosure.**   

    **_We want to be very clear: We will not obtain personally identifying information about you when you visit our site, unless you choose to provide such information to us. Except as might be required by law, we do not share any information we receive with outside parties._**

Cookies 

When you visit some websites, their webservers generate pieces of information known as cookies. Some cookies collect personal information to recognize your computer in the future. This is not the case at www.usbr.gov, where we only use non-persistent cookies or "per-session cookies." These cookies do not collect personal information on users and they are erased as soon as you leave our website.

Per-session cookies serve technical purposes like providing seamless navigation through www.usbr.gov. These cookies do not permanently record data and they are not stored on your computer's hard drive. www.usbr.gov cookies are stored in memory and are only available during an active browser session. Again, once you close your browser, the cookie disappears.  

Children's Privacy Protection 

The [Children's Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998](http://www.kidsprivacy.com/thelaw.htm) contains additional information on the protection of children's online privacy. A good resource for information on this law and additional resources for children is located at: [Just For Kids](http://www.ftc.gov/bcp/conline/edcams/kidzprivacy/kidz.htm) website. 

If you have any questions or comments about the information presented here, please forward them to us: [Bureau of Reclamation Privacy/FOIA Contacts](http://www.usbr.gov/foia/)

U.S. Department of the Interior  
FOIA/Privacy Staff  
OS/PIR, MS-5312  
1849 C Street, N.W.  
Washington, D.C. 20240 Phone: (202) 208-6194

Last reviewed: 3/16/06
